<item>
	<title>User and Customer Experience in a Member Services Organization</title>
	<link>http://uxclippings.posterous.com/user-and-customer-experience-in-a-member-serv</link>
	<pubDate>Tue Nov 09 14:27:00 -0800 2010</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Ziarek]]></dc:creator>
	
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://uxclippings.posterous.com/user-and-customer-experience-in-a-member-serv</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Interesting that AAA considers the phrase &ldquo;user experience&rdquo; to represent their digital interactions only. They clearly care about the rest of the customer experience, its just a distinction I&rsquo;m not sure most people make.</p>

<p>It helps that AAA embeds the customer experience into their fabric:</p>

<blockquote class="posterous_medium_quote"><p>We came to realize very early on in the process that customer experience is not an operational unit, but it is a cultural shift. It is a competency. It’s something that is shared by all and needs to be a commitment from all.</p></blockquote>

<p>Too often I see UX treated as something that can be bolted on, instead of something that needs top-down, end-to-end support throughout the organization. What good is a beautiful persona-driven website if the product developers are working toward different goals?</p>

<p><a href="http://uxmag.com/strategy/user-and-customer-experience-in-a-member-services-organization">http://uxmag.com/strategy/user-and-customer-experience-in-a-member-services-o...</a></p>

<p>(As an aside, I wish every video came with a transcript. Am I the only person that prefers to read articles over watching them?)</p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Interesting that AAA considers the phrase “user experience” to represent their digital interactions only. They clearly care about the rest of the customer experience, its just a distinction I’m not sure most people make. It helps that AAA embeds t...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Tue Nov 09 14:27:00 -0800 2010</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>Tue Nov 09 14:27:00 -0800 2010</wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_id>33007100</wp:post_id>
	<wp:post_name>user-and-customer-experience-in-a-member-serv</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
